Hello, it's great to have you back. This is week 6, and the topic of this
大家好 欢迎来到第6周的课程
week is partial differential equations in image processing.
本周我们将学习图像处理中的偏微分方程
Some of you might remember, some of you might know what partial differential
大家也许还记得 什么是偏微分方程
equations are. Some of you might not remember when you
但也许有的人已经不记得什么时候学过了
studied that, maybe a long time ago, maybe just a few years ago.
可能是很久以前 也可能是几年前
But don't worry because every other week this is going to be a very self
但是不用担心 因为每周的课程都是独立自给式的
containing week. Before I give you a bit more of details
在详细讲述这周内容之前
of what we are going to learn this week let me try to explain to you what we mean
我将为大家大致介绍一下偏微分方程
by partial differential equations what is kind of this new area.
以及这个新的领域
Relatively new area in imagine processing but certainly new for us in this class.
相对而言 这是图像处理中的一个新领域 在我们的课程中也是如此
So far we have been considering images at discrete objects in the computer.
迄今为止 我们对计算机中离散形式的图像已经有了一定的认识
If we look for example at the still image.
以这幅静态图像为例
We already talked it looks continuous to us but actually it is a connection of
这幅图像看起来是连续的 但实际上
pixels so its like this great two dimensional array of pixels as we have
它是很多个像素点组成的 就像这儿展示的一个二维像素矩阵
represented here now they are so close to each other we already talked about
我们已经讨论过分辨率 这些像素点挨得如此之紧
resolution they're so close to each other that it looks like a continuous image,
以至于这幅图像看起来像是连续的
but actually it is a discreet object. It's representing the computer as a
但实际上是离散的 它在计算机中作为一个离散对象显示
discreet object. The same happens with movies.
电影也是如此
We already know that movies are discrete object.
大家都知道 影片是由离散的画面组成的
They look continuous to us, like this movie that we are watching here, because
看起来是连续的动画 像这个影片
the sampling in time is basically very fast, and that's why our perception
这是因为在时间上的采样很快
perceives this as a continuous object, but we already know that this is a
这也就是为什么我们感知到的是连续对象 但我们已经知道这是离散的
discrete object. 30 frames per second, 24 frames per
每秒30帧 或者每秒24帧
second. So images and videos are discreet both in
图像和视频在空间上都是离散的
space. In time and also at the gray levels.
在时间和灰度级上也是离散的
They look continuous to us but they are discreet objects.
它们看起来是连续的但实际上是离散的
Now that leads us to what we have been doing most of these five previous weeks
现在 我们回顾一下前五周所学的
using tools from discreet representations from discreet mathematics because we have
我们使用了离散表示法和离散数学的工具
discreet objects in the computer. So what's different when we start talking
因为在计算机里 我们面对的是离散的对象
about partial differential equations. What's different is that we're going to
那么偏微分方程有什么不同呢？
start considering continuous objects. So what we consider discreet objects the
不同在于我们将会考虑连续的对象
way that videos and images are represented in the computer we see for
用离散对象表示图像或视频的时候 我们总是谈论求和
example, sums. We never saw the sign of an integral we
我们从来没有涉及过积分
always talk about sums we talked about discreet operations.
我们总是讨论求和离散运算
Also, every time we saw kind of a continuous object a derivative which is a
同样地 每当遇到某种连续运算 比如导数
toll from calculus is a continuous object then we immediately discretize it.
导数是微积分中针对连续对象的运算 我们把它离散化
Remember, we talked about, for example, it's derivative.
记住 我们谈论的例子是导数
Derivative indicates direction, and we say, okay, let's do plus one and minus
导数表示沿着某个方向求导 我们可以在这里构造一个+1和-1
one here. So immediately we redefine its discreet
这样的话 就可以重新定义导数的离散形式
counterpart because we want to be in a discreet wall.
因为运算需要在一个离散的环境中进行
We want to be in a discreet space. The area of partial differential
我们想要在离散空间进行处理 但从偏微分方程的角度来说
equations says forget about that the area of partial differential equations has a
不应该局限于这个条件 偏微分方程的应用领域
completely different approach and says images are continuous objects do not
有一个完全不同的方法 图像是连续的对象
treat them as discreet images anymore that's just an artifact of computer
不该将其作为离散的对象来处理 这只是计算机处理的人为产物
representations. Treat them as continuous objects.
图像本来就应该被看成是连续的
And then you basically are going to be talking about image processing that's
接下来就要用无穷小算子的迭代运算进行图像处理
iterations of infinite decimal operators, things that happen at very, very small
无穷小算子迭代运算是在很小的范围内进行迭代
scale we iterate them. And when we are iterating them, actually,
在迭代过程中 实际上
we get these partial differential equations, but once again if you don't
就得到了偏微分方程 如果你一下子没有明白这是怎么回事
remember exactly what they are, we are going to explain that in the next videos.
在接下来的视频中会为你详细解释
Don't worry about that, the key concept is here.
不要担心那个问题 关键概念在这儿
Images are not discreet objects, images are continuous.
图像不是离散的而是连续的
So go and gather up all of your algorithms that are in your continuous
因此运用连续域中所有的算法
domain. Treat images as continuous objects, and
将图像当做连续的对象
then you can do partial differential equations you can also differentiate
然后就可以使用偏微分方程和微分几何
geometry, tools that are from continuous mathematics.
以及其他连续域的数学方法
All of a sudden, they are valid. They're powerful for basically discreet
突然间 这些工具都能用了 它们在离散图像处理中十分强大
image processing, but then you ask yourself, wait a second.
但你会马上发现一个问题
You gather up them, but my images are still discreet objects in my computer.
现在有了这么多连续域的方法 但我计算机中的图像还是离散的
But here comes to the rescue, numerical analysis.
不用担心 这有一个解决方法 那就是数值分析
Numerical analysis is exactly the area that says how do I implement continuous
数值分析可以告诉我怎样实现连续域的算法
algorithms? How do I implement continuous mathematics
如何在离散域中 比如计算机中 利用连续域的数学工具
in discrete domains like a computer? So you go and develop algorithms with
因此能继续利用连续域的数学工具开发算法
tools of continuous mathematics and then. Numerical analysis comes to the rescue
然后采用数值分析
once we need to implement those algorithms in the computer.
使得可以在计算机中实现这些算法
So it's kind of a different paradigm. It's not better, its not worse.
所以这是一种不同的范式 它既不更好 也不更差
It's different than the paradigm that we were used to before, when we consider
仅仅是与我们之前用过的范式不同而已
images from the very beginning as discreet objects.
之前我们一开始就把图像当作离散的来考虑
Now, why?
现在为什么不了呢？
Why is this happening now? What's going on?
现在为什么会出现这些？ 接下来又会怎样？
Why do we move from this, from this completely discreet, that basically if we
为什么要改变 不再用离散的方法？
look historically, has mostly dominated image and video processing for years and
这么多年 离散化在处理图像和视频中可谓历史悠久
years, until basically about ten years ago, and of course there are a number of
直到差不多十年前 连续性计算工具开始出现在图像处理中
reasons why these continuous tools appear in image processing one is computers we
究其原因 其一 计算机飞速发展 功能愈加强大
can more powerful and then numerical algorithms to implement this continuous
其二 从前无法利用计算机计算的连续数学 【未完成版本】
math that were impossible to have in a computer we can actually do able in even
数值算法使之成为可能
small and personal computers of course every.
甚至在这些小巧的个人电脑上
New tools can because some people moved into the area and we should never forget
当然 每个新工具的出现都经过了人们的努力
about the influence of people. So a lot of people in the last ten years
我们永远不要忘记他们的贡献 近十年来
or so that were interested in continuous mathematics also became interested in
很多对连续性数学感兴趣的人 也渐渐地对图像处理产生了兴趣
image processing and they brought their tools, their expertise into image
他们将这些工具和自身的专长应用到图像处理上
processing. Now we're going to see, as I said we're
现在我们会看一些例子
going to see examples. I am going to provide you the background
为大家介绍一下背景知识
but. What is it bringing to us?
但连续域图像处理的研究又给我们带来了什么呢？
It's going to bring a number of things. It brings new concepts.
它将带来许多东西 比如新的概念
It brings accuracy. This is a very important thing, because
它引入了精度 这非常重要
we are in continuous domain, and then we implement by numerical,
因为现在处于一个连续的空间 通过数值算法来执行
algorithms. The accuracy will depend on the
精度将依赖于算法的实施
implementation, not on the design of the algorithm.
而不是算法的设计
The algorithm is designed in the continuous domain, so there is no
算法是在连续域中设计的
intrinsic accuracy. Depending how much I'm willing to invest,
因此没有内在的精度 而是取决于我愿意投入多少的运算和资源
computation and resources for example, in the implementation that will determine
给大家举一个计算的例子 在实施过程中
the actual accuracy of the algorithm. It's not intrinsic to the algorithm.
就决定了算法的精度 对于算法来说 这不是固有的
When I define a derivative at plus minus, plus one minus one,
但我们用+1和-1定义导数时
I'm done. I have defined the accuracy of my
实际上就已经定义了算法的精度
algorithm. Now if I define the continuum and, and
现在 如果我在连续域中进行定义
then say do the derivative the best you can,
尽你最大的努力 提高导数的精度
I leave the door open to very high accuracy techniques.
这样就为高精度的技术保留了可能性
Another thing that was broad, that we are not going to discuss a lot in this class,
另外一个 我们不准备在课堂上进行说明
and certainly not in this week, is very formal analysis.
当然也不是这周 那就是形式分析
A lot of the techniques that came from the area of partial differential
许多用于图像处理的偏微分方程方面的技术
equations to image processing have very formal analysis.
都有非常形式化的分析
You can prove theorems, you can prove that what your doing is right even before
你可以证明这些理论是对的
your going and implementing the algorithm.
在你应用实施这些算法之前
So it's one of the most mathematical areas in image and video processing.
所以 这是图像和视频处理中最数学化的领域之一
I'm not saying its the only one, but it's one of the most mathematical areas.
我不敢说这是最数学化的一个 但确实是最数学化的之一
And the consequences of this is that partial differential equation tools
而这样的结果是 偏微分方程这个工具
brought a lot of state of the al-, algorithms.
提供了很多种算法
But I think one of the most important things, and I want to leave you before we
但在我们详细讲述之前 我认为最重要的是
go into details with this take home message, is that there are new tools and
我们有新的工具和新的书籍
new books in the bookshelf. So when you bring a new theory into an
因此 当你在某个领域提出一个新的理论时
area, you say, okay all these new frameworks
你可以认为 所有这些新的框架体系都已经存在
are now allowed. And it always good to have more tools to
而且有更多的工具来解决实际问题是很好的
solve real problems, as we are going to see this week and a bit next week.
就像我们本周 还有下周将要学习到的一样
So, what we're going to do this week is I'm going to give you the tools to
接下来在本周 我会给你们一些工具
understand the underlying and the simplest possible tools to understand the
用基本的和最简单的工具
area of partial differential equations in image processing.
去理解偏微分方程在图像处理中的应用
We're going to filter in examples that is going to show you to understand.
我将举一些例子 来帮助你理解
Remember, last week we discussed active counters, that's one example of the use
上周 我们讨论过主动轮廓
of partial differential equations in image processing as we are going to see
这将是偏微分方程在图像处理中应用的一个范例
very soon in one of the future videos. And we are also going to talk next week
在接下来的视频中就会看到 下个星期
about imaging painting and some of the algorithms we are going to subscribe
我们会讲到图像修复 其中的一些算法
there are based on partial differential equations.
也是基于偏微分方程
As I said, is one of the most mathematical areas that we're going to
如我所说 这是最数学化的领域之一
discuss during these nine weeks of classes in image and video processing.
这是最数学化的部分之一
But there's nothing to worry, because I'm going to introduce you to the basic
但没有什么好担心的 仅仅是向大家介绍一下基本概念
concepts and the basic tools that you need to understand the fundamental
还有一些基本工具 这些工具有助于你们理解
concepts behind this area of partial differential equations in image
偏微分方程应用于图像处理的基本概念
processing. And we're going to start learning about
接下来的视频中 我们就将学习这些概念
those concepts right in the next video. Thank you.
谢谢